David Locke Papers MS122
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
David Locke Papers
1988 -- 2011
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Locke, David
MS122
1.2 Linear Feet 1 record carton
1038 Digital Object(s)
Conditions Governing Access
This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Arrangement
This collection is organized in three series: Oral History Interviews; Dagomba Dance Drumming materials; Agbadza collection.
Biographical / Historical
David Locke is Professor of Music at Tufts University. He earned his B.A., 1972, and Ph.D., 1978, both from Wesleyan University. Locke is an ethnomusicologist specializing in traditional African music and dance. He began teaching at Tufts part−time as the director of the African Music Ensemble in 1979, eventually earning tenure in the early 1990s. He is founder and director of the Agbekor Drum and Dance Society, and author of Drum Gahu: The Rhythms of West African Music.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains audio and textual files created to provide access to David Locke's collection of Agbadza and Dagomba drumming and song.
Ethnomusicology; Dagomba (Ghana); Locke, David; Faculty research
- Oral History Interviews, 1988 -- 2007; MS122.001; 1.2 Linear Feet Record carton contains 7 CDs, 10 cassettes, 2 3.5" floppy disks, 4 folders of transcripts, and 2 binders containing Lunna life story draft.
  Scope and Contents
  Interviews with Alhaji Abubakari Lunna
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Dagomba project draft material, oral history tapes, life histories and Agbadza CDs, 1988 -- 2007; MS122.001-GB (Box 1)
    This material is not yet processed, but it is open for research.
- Dagomba Dance Drumming materials, 1989 -- 2010; MS122.002; 788 Digital Object(s)
  This series contains audio and textual files created to provide digital access to David Locke's Dagomba Dance Drumming material.
  - Takai, group dance, 2001 -- 2010; MS122.002.001; 152 Digital Object(s)
    Takai is one of the oldest drum rhythms of the Dagomba, and the story tells of how they came to be so close to the Mossi tribe. There was a war going on between the Dagomba and Mossi, and a Dagomba woman got lost in the bush and was eventually found by a Mossi hunter. Years later, when there was once again conflict between the Dagomba and Mossi, the woman's history came to light, and because of this connection they halted the fighting. Combined, the drum language for all the parts says "chief says listen, stop the fight."
    - Story of Takai, 2002; MS122.002.001.00001; Locke, David; Lunna, Abubakari
      Told by Abubakari Lunna on March 29, 2002. Edited by David Locke. Story of the origins of the Takai dance and rhythm played by Dagbani drummers.
      African drumming; Ghanaian music; Talking drums; Dagomba drumming
    - Takai lead lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00002; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Takai lead lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00003; Locke, David
      African drumming; Ghanaian music; Talking drums; Dagomba drumming; Musical notation
    - Takai lead lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00004; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Takai lead lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00005; Locke, David
    - Takai lead lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.001.00006; Locke, David
    - Takai answer lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00007; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Takai answer lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00008; Locke, David
    - Takai answer lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00009; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Takai answer lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00010; Locke, David
    - Takai answer lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.001.00011; Locke, David
    - Takai answer gung-gong vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00012; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Takai answer gung-gong vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00013; Locke, David
    - Takai answer gung-gong drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00014; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Takai answer gung-gong drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00015; Locke, David
    - Takai answer gung-gong drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.001.00016; Locke, David
    - Takai lead gung-gong vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00017; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Takai lead gung-gong vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00018; Locke, David
    - Takai lead gung-gong drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00019; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Takai lead gung-gong drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00020; Locke, David
    - Takai lead gung-gong drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.001.00021; Locke, David
    - Takai ensemble rhythm notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00022; Locke, David
    - Takai drumming ensemble audio, live, 2008; MS122.002.001.00023; Agbekor Drum and Dance Society, Dagomba Section; Goldmann, Jonathan
    - Takai drumming ensemble audio, multitrack aggregate, 2005; MS122.002.001.00024; Lunna, Abubakari; Wasserman, Luke
    - Nyagboli (Takai) lead lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00025; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Nyagboli (Takai) lead lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00026; Locke, David
    - Nyagboli (Takai) lead lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00027; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Nyagboli (Takai) lead lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00028; Locke, David
    - Nyagboli (Takai) lead lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.001.00029; Locke, David
    - Nyagboli (Takai) answer lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00030; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Nyagboli (Takai) answer lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00031; Locke, David
    - Nyagboli (Takai) answer lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00032; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Nyagboli (Takai) answer lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00033; Locke, David
    - Nyagboli (Takai) answer lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.001.00034; Locke, David
    - Nyagboli (Takai) answer gung-gong vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00035; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Nyagboli (Takai) answer gung-gong vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00036; Locke, David
    - Nyagboli (Takai) answer gung-gong drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00037; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Nyagboli (Takai) answer gung-gong drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00038; Locke, David
    - Nyagboli (Takai) answer gung-gong drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.001.00039; Locke, David
    - Nyagboli (Takai) lead gung-gong vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00040; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Nyagboli (Takai) lead gung-gong vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00041; Locke, David
    - Nyagboli (Takai) lead gung-gong drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00042; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Nyagboli (Takai) lead gung-gong drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00043; Locke, David
    - Nyagboli (Takai) lead gung-gong drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.001.00044; Locke, David
    - Nyagboli (Takai) ensemble rhythm notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00045; Locke, David
    - Nyagboli (Takai) drumming ensemble audio, live, 2008; MS122.002.001.00046; Agbekor Drum and Dance Society, Dagomba Section; Goldmann, Jonathan
    - Nyagboli (Takai) drumming ensemble audio, multitrack aggregate, 2005; MS122.002.001.00047; Lunna, Abubakari; Wasserman, Luke
    - Tanchili Gong lead lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00048; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Tanchili Gong lead lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00049; Locke, David
    - Tanchili Gong lead lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00050; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Tanchili Gong lead lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00051; Locke, David
    - Tanchili Gong lead lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.001.00052; Locke, David
    - Tanchili Gong answer lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00053; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Tanchili Gong answer lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00054; Locke, David
    - Tanchili Gong answer lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00055; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Tanchili Gong answer lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00056; Locke, David
    - Tanchili Gong answer lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.001.00057; Locke, David
    - Tanchili Gong lead gung-gong vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00058; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Tanchili Gong lead gung-gong vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00059; Locke, David
    - Tanchili Gong lead gung-gong drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00060; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Tanchili Gong lead gung-gong drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00061; Locke, David
    - Tanchili Gong lead gung-gong drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.001.00062; Locke, David
    - Tanchili Gong ensemble rhythm notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00063; Locke, David
    - Tanchili Gong drumming ensemble audio, live, 2008; MS122.002.001.00064; Agbekor Drum and Dance Society, Dagomba Section; Goldmann, Jonathan
    - Tanchili Gong drumming ensemble audio, multitrack aggregate, 2005; MS122.002.001.00065; Lunna, Abubakari; Wasserman, Luke
    - Ngunda Nyuli lead lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00066; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Ngunda Nyuli lead lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00067; Locke, David
    - Ngunda Nyuli lead lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00068; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Ngunda Nyuli lead lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00069; Locke, David
    - Ngunda Nyuli lead lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.001.00070; Locke, David
    - Ngunda Nyuli answer lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00071; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Ngunda Nyuli answer lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00072; Locke, David
    - Ngunda Nyuli answer lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00073; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Ngunda Nyuli answer lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00074; Locke, David
    - Ngunda Nyuli answer lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.001.00075; Locke, David
    - Ngunda Nyuli lead gung-gong vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00076; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Ngunda Nyuli lead gung-gong vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00077; Locke, David
    - Ngunda Nyuli lead gung-gong drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00078; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Ngunda Nyuli lead gung-gong drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00079; Locke, David
    - Ngunda Nyuli lead gung-gong drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.001.00080; Locke, David
    - Ngunda Nyuli ensemble rhythm notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00081; Locke, David
    - Ngunda Nyuli drumming ensemble audio, live, 2008; MS122.002.001.00082; Agbekor Drum and Dance Society, Dagomba Section; Goldmann, Jonathan
    - Ngunda Nyuli drumming ensemble audio, multitrack aggregate, 2005; MS122.002.001.00083; Lunna, Abubakari; Wasserman, Luke
    - Kondaliya lead lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00084; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya lead lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00085; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya lead lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00086; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya lead lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00087; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya lead lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.001.00088; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya answer lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00089; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya answer lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00090; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya answer lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00091; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya answer lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00092; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya answer lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.001.00093; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya answer gung-gong vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00094; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya answer gung-gong vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00095; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya answer gung-gong vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00096; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya answer gung-gong drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00097; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya answer gung-gong drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.001.00098; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya lead gung-gong vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00099; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya lead gung-gong vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00100; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya lead gung-gong drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.001.00101; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya lead gung-gong drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00102; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya lead gung-gong drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.001.00103; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya ensemble rhythm notation, 2010; MS122.002.001.00104; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya drumming ensemble audio, live, 2008; MS122.002.001.00105; Agbekor Drum and Dance Society, Dagomba Section; Goldmann, Jonathan
    - Kondaliya drumming ensemble audio, multitrack aggregate, 2005; MS122.002.001.00106; Lunna, Abubakari; Wasserman, Luke
    - Takai lead gung-gong vocables transcription, 2010; MS122.002.001.00107; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya lead lunga vocables transcription, 2010; MS122.002.001.00108; Locke, David
    - Kondaliya lead lunga drumming transcription, 2010; MS122.002.001.00109; Locke, David
    - Takai Kondaliya lead lunga drum language audio (1) to zunga yaa ni, 2010; MS122.002.001.00110; Locke, David
    - Takai Kondaliya lead lunga drum language audio (2) to zungo to zungo to zungo yaa ni, 2010; MS122.002.001.00111; Locke, David
    - Takai Kondaliya lead lunga drum language audio (3) wogi m-bo m-binya bagaka ka zungo yaa ni, 2010; MS122.002.001.00112; Locke, David
    - Takai Kondaliya answer lunga drum language audio (1) naa cheng, 2010; MS122.002.001.00113; Locke, David
    - Takai Ngunda Nyuli lead lunga drum language audio (1) nyam o, 2010; MS122.002.001.00114; Locke, David
    - Takai Ngunda Nyuli lead lunga drum language audio (2) ngunda nyuli ngunda nyuli, 2010; MS122.002.001.00115; Locke, David
    - Takai Ngunda Nyuli lead lunga drum language audio (3) ngunda nyuli -da nyuli -da nyuli, 2010; MS122.002.001.00116; Locke, David
    - Takai Ngunda Nyuli answer lunga drum language audio (1) nyam o, 2010; MS122.002.001.00117; Locke, David
    - Takai Nyagboli lead lunga drum language audio (1) Azemma guya no tiligi, 2010; MS122.002.001.00118; Locke, David
    - Takai Nyagboli lead lunga drum language audio (2) gno bie la lariga ka nye ba, 2010; MS122.002.001.00119; Locke, David
    - Takai Nyagboli answer lunga drum language audio (1) gbam o, 2010; MS122.002.001.00120; Locke, David
    - Takai Takai lead lunga drum language audio (1a) to nin wum nin wum nin wuma, 2010; MS122.002.001.00121; Locke, David
    - Takai Takai lead lunga drum language audio (1b) to nin wum nin wum nin wuma, 2010; MS122.002.001.00122; Locke, David
    - Takai Takai lead lunga drum language audio (2a) to nin wum naa yen nin wuma, 2010; MS122.002.001.00123; Locke, David
    - Takai Takai lead lunga drum language audio (2b) to nin wum naa yen nin wuma, 2010; MS122.002.001.00124; Locke, David
    - Takai Takai answer lunga drum language audio (1) nin wum nin wum, 2010; MS122.002.001.00125; Locke, David
    - Takai Tanchili Gong lead lunga drum language audio (1) tanchili gong, 2010; MS122.002.001.00126; Locke, David
    - Takai Tanchili Gong lead lunga drum language audio (2) tanchili gong, 2010; MS122.002.001.00127; Locke, David
    - Takai Tanchili Gong answer lunga drum language audio (1) nyam o, 2010; MS122.002.001.00128; Locke, David
    - Takai Kondaliya lead gung-gong drum language audio (1) chem sa ka ti cheng, 2010; MS122.002.001.00129; Locke, David
    - Takai Kondaliya lead gung-gong drum language audio (2) ka ti cheng ka ti cheng cheng ka i cheng chema sa ka ti cheng cheng, 2010; MS122.002.001.00130; Locke, David
    - Takai Kondaliya lead gung-gong drum language audio (3a) chem sa ka ti cheng ka ti chema sa kati cheng, 2010; MS122.002.001.00131; Locke, David
    - Takai Kondaliya lead gung-gong drum language audio (3b) chem sa ka ti cheng ka ti chema sa kati cheng, 2010; MS122.002.001.00132; Locke, David
    - Takai Kondaliya lead gung-gong drum language audio (4) chem sa ka ti cheng to chema sa kati cheng, 2010; MS122.002.001.00133; Locke, David
    - Takai Kondaliya anwer gung-gong drum language audio (1) naa cheng, 2010; MS122.002.001.00134; Locke, David
    - Takai Nunda Nyuli lead gung-gong drum language audio (1) ka sampoa zolbee ka dim sa, 2010; MS122.002.001.00135; Locke, David
    - Takai Nunda Nyuli lead gung-gong drum language audio (2) ka dim ka dim ka dim sa, 2010; MS122.002.001.00136; Locke, David
    - Takai Nunda Nyuli lead gung-gong drum language audio (3a) sampoa zolbee sampoa zolbee ka dim sa, 2010; MS122.002.001.00137; Locke, David
    - Takai Nunda Nyuli lead gung-gong drum language audio (3b) sampoa zolbee sampoa zolbee ka dim sa, 2010; MS122.002.001.00138; Locke, David
    - Takai Nyagboli lead gung-gong drum language audio (1) ti be zabira mani bori o gbam o, 2010; MS122.002.001.00139; Locke, David
    - Takai Nyagboli lead gung-gong drum language audio (2) mani bori o mani bori o gbam o, 2010; MS122.002.001.00140; Locke, David
    - Takai Nyagboli lead gung-gong drum language audio (3) ti be zabira ti be zabira gbam o, 2010; MS122.002.001.00141; Locke, David
    - Takai Nyagboli lead gung-gong drum language audio (4) gbam o zali ma gbam o zali ma gbam o, 2010; MS122.002.001.00142; Locke, David
    - Takai Nyagboli lead gung-gong drum language audio (5) to to to to ka n-kanna, 2010; MS122.002.001.00143; Locke, David
    - Takai Nyagboli answer gung-gong drum language audio (1) gbam o, 2010; MS122.002.001.00144; Locke, David
    - Takai Takai lead gung-gong drum language audio (1) Var 1, 2010; MS122.002.001.00145; Locke, David
    - Takai Takai lead gung-gong drum language audio (2) Var 2, 2010; MS122.002.001.00146; Locke, David
    - Takai Takai lead gung-gong drum language audio (3) Var 3, 2010; MS122.002.001.00147; Locke, David
    - Takai Takai lead gung-gong drum language audio (4) Var 4, 2010; MS122.002.001.00148; Locke, David
    - Takai Takai answer gung-gong drum language audio (1) che zabli, 2010; MS122.002.001.00149; Locke, David
    - Takai Tanchili Gong lead gung-gong drum language audio (1) Var 1, 2010; MS122.002.001.00150; Locke, David
    - Takai Tanchili Gong lead gung-gong drum language audio (2) Var 2, 2010; MS122.002.001.00151; Locke, David
    - Takai Tanchili Gong lead gung-gong drum language audio (3) Var 3, 2010; MS122.002.001.00152; Locke, David
  - Tora, group dance, 1989 -- 2010; MS122.002.002; 58 Digital Object(s)
    Tora is among the oldest of the Dagomba drum stories. There came a time when a chief died having produced no sons, and they were forced to make a woman Yaa-naa. Another man who wanted the chieftaincy scared her out of the palace one night, forcing them to choose a new chief, and in accordance with his plan they chose him. The story of Tora is about the tragedy and misfortune that befell the man who violated tradition by scaring the Yaa-naa out of the palace to get the chieftaincy for himself.
    - Story of Tora, 1989; MS122.002.002.00001; Locke, David; Lunna, Abubakari
      Told by Abubakari Lunna on May 26 and June 3, 1989. Edited by David Locke. Story of the origins of the Tora dance and drumming rhythm, composed for funerals.
    - Tora lead lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.002.00002; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Tora lead lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.002.00003; Locke, David
    - Tora lead lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.002.00004; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Tora lead lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.002.00005; Locke, David
    - Tora lead lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.002.00006; Locke, David
    - Tora answer lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.002.00007; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Tora answer lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.002.00008; Locke, David
    - Tora answer lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.002.00009; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Tora answer lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.002.00010; Locke, David
    - Tora answer lunga drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.002.00011; Locke, David
    - Tora lead gung-gong vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.002.00012; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Tora lead gung-gong vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.002.00013; Locke, David
    - Tora lead gung-gong drumming audio (1), 2001; MS122.002.002.00014; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Tora lead gung-gong drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.002.00015; Locke, David
    - Tora lead gung-gong drum language text, 2010; MS122.002.002.00016; Locke, David
    - Tora drumming ensemble audio, live, 2008; MS122.002.002.00017; Agbekor Drum and Dance Society, Dagomba Section; Goldmann, Jonathan
    - Tora drumming ensemble audio, multitrack aggregate, 2005; MS122.002.002.00018; Lunna, Abubakari; Wasserman, Luke
    - Ayiko lead lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.002.00019; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Ayiko lead lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.002.00020; Locke, David
    - Ayiko lead lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.002.00021; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Ayiko lead lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.002.00022; Locke, David
    - Ayiko answer lunga vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.002.00023; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Ayiko answer lunga vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.002.00024; Locke, David
    - Ayiko answer lunga drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.002.00025; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Ayiko answer lunga drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.002.00026; Locke, David
    - Ayiko lead gung-gong vocables notation, 2010; MS122.002.002.00027; Locke, David
    - Ayiko lead gung-gong drumming audio, 2001; MS122.002.002.00028; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Ayiko lead gung-gong drumming notation, 2010; MS122.002.002.00029; Locke, David
    - Ayiko ensemble rhythm notation, 2010; MS122.002.002.00030; Locke, David
    - Ayiko drumming ensemble audio, live, 2008; MS122.002.002.00031; Agbekor Drum and Dance Society, Dagomba Section; Goldmann, Jonathan
    - Nyagboli (Tora) drumming ensemble audio, multitrack aggregate, 2005; MS122.002.002.00032; Lunna, Abubakari; Wasserman, Luke
    - Tora lead gung-gong drumming audio (2), 2001; MS122.002.002.00033; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Tora lead lunga vocables transcription, 2010; MS122.002.002.00034; Locke, David
    - Tora lead lunga drumming transcription (A), 2010; MS122.002.002.00035; Locke, David
    - Tora lead lunga drumming transcription (B), 2010; MS122.002.002.00036; Locke, David
    - Tora answer lunga vocables transcription, 2010; MS122.002.002.00037; Locke, David
    - Tora lead gung-gong vocables transcription, 2010; MS122.002.002.00038; Locke, David
    - Tora lead gung-gong drumming transcription (1), 2010; MS122.002.002.00039; Locke, David
    - Tora lead gung-gong drumming transcription (2), 2010; MS122.002.002.00040; Locke, David
    - Tora ensemble rhythm notation, 2010; MS122.002.002.00041; Locke, David
    - Ayiko lead lunga drumming transcription, 2010; MS122.002.002.00042; Locke, David
    - Ayiko lead gung-gong vocables transcription, 2010; MS122.002.002.00043; Locke, David
    - Ayiko lead gung-gong vocables audio, 2001; MS122.002.002.00044; Lunna, Abubakari; Locke, David
    - Tora Tora lead lunga drum language audio (1a, 1b) to nung jema ka ma n-je kurigu bi yebila, 2010; MS122.002.002.00045; Locke, David